SRI SAI NIKHITH VAKULABHARANAM

United Kingdom | Contact: +44 7586597557 | nikhithuk@gmail.com | LinkedIn: in/srisainikhith

Full Stack Developer

Having graduated with a MSc. in Computer Science with Industrial Placement from University of East London and over 4 years of IT Software Development experience, I am actively looking for Full-stack developer roles. I have the right to work in the UK and am willing to relocate. Committed to deliver top- notch solutions that align seamlessly with project goals, exceeding expectations

SKILLS AND CERTIFCATIONS

Core Competency:

Agile Project Management • Full Stack Development: Angular, .Net C#, SQL, MongoDB, MySQL • Documentation • Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) • Version Control • Quality Assurance and Testing: Jasmine, Karma • DevOps and Cloud Solutions: Azure, Google Cloud, AWS, Docker • Collaboration and communication • Integration with third-Party Tools • Cloud migration • Google Cloud optimization • Python

Certifications:

MTA-Database Administration Fundamentals • MTA-Networking Fundamentals • MATLAB Essentials • AWS Cloud Practitioner Essentials

EDUCATION

May 2022 - Feb 2024: University of East London, United Kingdom

Masters of Science in Computer Science with Industrial Placement: Distinction

- Specialization: Advanced Software Engineering, Big Data Analytics, Cloud Computing, Artificial Intelligence.
- Dissertation: Thesis on Tactile Sensing of Epidural Needle into Spinal Column

Apr 2015 - May 2019: Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University, India

Bachelor of Technology - Computer Science and Engineering: 2:1

- Specialization: Software Engineering, Database Fundamentals, Computer Networks, Information Security.
- Dissertation: Surveillance of people in defense organization using Object Recognition and TensorFlow Framework

WORK EXPERIENCE

June 2023 – Jan 2024: University of East London, UK as Research Scholar

Job Profile:

- Engaged in diverse projects during a 12-month placement, directing to the development of innovative solutions
- Generated and analyzed data for the IEEE dataset of 36700 records, gaining insights into open-source collaboration and publication processes
- Authored a systematic literature review on epidural needle tactile feedback, exhibiting independent judgment and responsibility by reviewing 365 papers
- Submitted a conference paper initiated a systematic literature review, and established a pavement maintenance system within 48 days, showcasing effective time management and professional commitment
- Prepared a literature review quality check, by applying an 8-question checklist to each study, emphasizing meticulous planning skills
- Improved multifaceted experiences that enriched work-based skills across 4 projects, laying a strong foundation for future academic and research pursuits

Technology Incorporated:

Scholarly Research, Literature, Research and Development (R&D), Arduino, Biomedical Engineering, Haptic technology, Application Engineering

May 2021 - Dec 2022: Qualminds, India as Senior Software Engineer

Job Profile:

Authored exposure to latest .net technologies during the initial 6-month probation period

- Implemented more than 6 vehicle dealer applications that includes Ford, Mitsubishi, Subaru, Honda, Bentley, BMW, Volkswagen encompassing Email and mobile communication apps
- Revamped the end-to-end process of triggering, scheduling, and generating comprehensive reports for emails, achieving a 98% efficiency rate
- Conceptualized tools like Hangfire Worker, Rabbit MQ, and cloud BI tools, seamlessly integrated with Google Cloud Services
- Managed cloud database platforms such as BigQuery powered by Google and employed Redis for cache services, resulting in a 20% reduction in query response time
- Designed and built Docker containers to improve deployment efficiency and portability
- Operated in an agile environment, understanding, and adapting to requirements and changes provided by the product owner
- Learned and influenced to the team's success, receiving healthy support from colleagues, resulting in a 15% increase in team productivity
- Executed repository cloning and created branches and tags from the master to separate build systems after milestone releases
- Monitored builds using Continuous Integration tools like Atlassian and Jenkins, ensuring a 99% success rate in build reliability and deployment consistency

Technology Incorporated:

.NET Framework, Microsoft SQL Server, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Angular, Hangfire Worker, Rabbit MQ, BigQuery (Google Cloud), Redis

Apr 2019 - May 2021: Audree Infotech, INDIA as Full-stack Software Developer

Job Profile:

- Co-ordinated to 7+ projects such as Annual Product Quality Report, Laboratory Information Management System, Quality Management System, HRM Project, and Learning Management System
- Acquired essential skills in 5 months, transitioning to active development of ERP solutions
- Served as a Team Lead for a group of 6, overseeing the development process without major flaws and persuading the importance of collaboration
- Led the migration of the Electronic Log Management System project from Web Forms to an ASP.NET 3.0 applications, implementing a modernized architecture
- Implemented Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) practices, streamlining development and deployment processes
- Incorporated version control systems, particularly Git, to manage the project's source code. Created Git repositories, implementing secure access through keys, preparing a controlled and facilitated environment for collaborative development
- Demonstrated a commitment to continuous learning and hands-on application of technologies, completing 15+ skill enhancement courses and certifications

Technology Incorporated:

.Net MVC, Angular, jQuery, JS, SQL Server, IIS Hosting, DevOps tools (CI/CD), GMP standards, .Net API's, Git, Docker, Jenkins, AWS, SonarQube, Slack, Microsoft Teams

Feb 2016 – May 2017: Centinel Spark Technologies, India as Student Intern Job Profile:

- Acquired proficiency in micro-controllers and the programming particularly in two main programming languages i.e., C++ and Python
- Introduced to the developing 7 proof-of-concept models in IoT, including Farm Automation, Blind Stick, Home Automation, Rubik's Cube Solver, PIR Robots, Lego Drones, and Mobile Workstations
- Guided in the Government STEM Scheme, training 300+ high school students on Raspberry Pi and Python basics
- Gained exposure to ethical hacking concepts such as Decrypting Cipher and Encryption, utilizing tools like MP3Stego, OpenStego, and iWatermark
- Received training on basic 2D gaming using Unity Engine, covering key aspects of game development
- Internship provided hands-on experience in diverse technologies, fostering problem-solving skills through active participation in more than 15 projects

Technology Incorporated:

Micro-controllers, IoT, Python, Unity Engine, Raspberry Pi, Hmac and Sha-256 Cipher encryption and decryption algorithms